Network Engineer

Network Engineer - CoNetrix

Midland, TX - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/12f9d173c336d577

Telecommunication Technician, Satellite Systems Operator, Systems and Network Administrator, and Technical Control Facility Operator. Significant expertise within the field of Telecommunications Systems and Satellite Communications. Effective at managing satellite communications terminals, associated baseband equipment. Troubleshoot and repair ancillary laptops and phones. Excellent at switching, routing, and multiplexing technologies. Proficient in providing training opportunities for professional growth and development of the employees. Professional support of the management personnel and prompt assistance. Cisco CCENT, CompTIA A+ and Security+ Certifications. GVF 510. Microsoft MCSA Windows 10

MAJOR ACCOMPLISHMENTS:

- Implemented plans for multiple Authorized Service Interruptions to accomplish maintenance and upgrades as part of AN/GSC 52 modernization.
- Traveled to remote sites on numerous occasions in Afghanistan as the lone subject matter expert to repair essential Satellite or Line-of-Sight links.
- Trained 13 technicians on daily operations and equipment characteristics and capabilities resulting in all technicians passing the company's site level 1 certification on first attempt. Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Network Engineer

CoNetrix - Lubbock, TX - February 2015 to Present

Supervisor: Adam Cates

- Local Engineer for Midland customers. Saved CoNetrix the cost of driving an engineer from Lubbock to Midland.
- Provided All-in-one IT support from help desk and Active Directory issues to server upgrades and network infrastructure support.
- Endeared myself to customers to the point that they would ask for me by name to fix their IT issues.

Senior VSAT Field Engineer

RigNet - Midland, TX - November 2013 to February 2015

Supervisor: Josue Martinez (Sway) (432) 208-7260 (may contact)

- Professionally completed over 350 VSAT and RF LOS installs, iDirect and SpaceNet
- Trained 4 new employees on proper installation procedures and RigNet SOP
- Consistently successfully finding solutions to problems that vex NOC engineering

Telecommunications Tech, Webmaster

Remote Communications, Inc - Odessa, TX - June 2013 to November 2013

Supervisor: Sean Crawford (432) 212-5879 (may contact)

- Professionally completed over 200 VSAT installs or reinstalls, often subcontracting for Harris Caprock and Global Data Systems, primarily iDirect systems, some Hughes
- Created Remote Communications transit case for rental systems

- Created and maintained remotecommunications.net and it's ticketing system
- Served as a Subject Matter Expert for Cisco networking, RF LOS shots

Senior RF/Satellite Communications Technician/Instructor

Satellite Communications - December 2012 to June 2013

Supervisor: Chris Leslie, (718) 764-7471, Stefan Nichols, stnichols@telecomsys.com, may contact

- Ensured proper corrective and preventive maintenance of satellite terminals and all ancillary equipment to include VoIP phones and laptops.
- Developed an implemented training programs on SATCOM, Line-of-Sight theory and implementation of Very Small Aperture (VSAT); trained over 40 marines.
- Served as a Subject Matter Expert for Satellite Communications to include Master Reference Terminal (MRT) operations and Linkway 2100 and S2 modem programming.
- Ensured proper configuration and operation of Cisco 2811 and Cisco 3825 routers in SWAN/SNAP/WPPL network stacks.

Network Analyst

Chevron - Midland, TX - June 2012 to December 2012

Supervisor: Joe Detiveaux (432) 425-4793 (please contact)

- Learned analog and VoIP side of telecom to include Cisco Call Manager
- Supported multiple VSAT installations and troubleshooting
- Learned oilfield safety expectations and field ticket and JSA paperwork standards
- Serves as a Subject Matter Expert for Cisco networking, RF LOS shots and VSATs

Forward Support Representative (Satellite Technician)

Telecommunication Systems, Inc - Camp Dwyer - May 2011 to June 2012

Senior Satellite Communications Technician / Section Chief

HIANG, Charlie Company, 29th Brigade Special Troop Battalion - Kapolei, HI - 2009 to 2011

- Installed, repaired, and performed equipment testing of satellite communications systems to ensure compliance with operational and functional standards.
- Acted as a Lead point-of-contact for the troubleshooting and maintenance of 3 terminals.
- Provided leadership and guidance for 3 soldier team in the operation of the terminal.
- Received new AN/TSC 185 Satellite Transportable Terminal (STT) as part of transition into WIN-T Joint Node Network (JNN); managed proper inventory control.
- Distributed VSATs; trained appropriate personnel to effectively operate them.
- Validated FDMA (Raydyne modem) and TDMA (Linkway S2 modem) operations for Battalion missions.

Satellite Systems Operator & Maintenance Specialist / Team Leader

US Army, Kunia Satcom - Kunia, HI - 2006 to 2009

Supervisor: Jonathan O'Donnell, (813) 786-9913, may be contacted

- Coordinated the operations and maintenance programs for the AN/GSC-52 Satellite terminal, HVAC and backup power systems.
- Supervised the performance of 3-7 technicians responsible for satellite communication operations; corrected deterioration/failure of any equipment or links.
- Coordinated with system supply lead to order tier-3 maintenance and replacement equipment.
- Scheduled, planned, conducted and evaluated professional training and orientation for new personnel and shift technicians.
- Directed the operations of multiple modems, multiplexers and encryption devices to include OM-73, BEM, EBEM, LRM, TSSP, ETSSP, FCC-100, KIV-7, KIV-19, KG-84, KG-175.

Node Center and Satellite Systems Operator / Maintenance Specialist

US Army, 334 Signal Company - Fort Lewis, WA - 2002 to 2005

Assisted with the creation of documentation for new communications equipment including the Brigade Subscriber Node (next generation node center) and the SMART-T (HMMWV mounted Milstar satellite system - 5' antenna).

- Provided consistent communications for the 3rd Brigade, 2nd Infantry Division during Iraq deployment.
- Provided technical support for the Brigade's operations.
- Participated in field exercises preparatory to a one year deployment to Mosul (Iraq)

Technical Control Facility Operator

US Army, Kunia Satcom - 2000 to 2001

Was chosen as one of only three soldiers to relocate to the isolated Suwon ROK Air Force Base Tech Control Facility due to independence and technical proficiency.

• Provided professional assistance and support in Tech Control Facility operations.

EDUCATION

Western Governor's University December 2017

Communication Systems

US Army Signal Center - Fort Gordon, GA 2006

MILITARY SERVICE

Service Country: US Branch: Army Rank: SGT

July 1999 to March 2009